双语特效字幕
百度贴吧
衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译  北落师门
翻译  旧镇老翁
君临 King's Landing
翻译  Violet_Rosa
红堡
Red Keep
翻译  托曼
赫伦堡
Harrenhal
校对  surhine
校对  夏大猫子
派
Pyke
克
城
派
Pyke
克
城
复校  pksunking
临冬城 Winterfell
精校  龙的命根子
时间轴   旧镇老翁  poplar
后期   旧镇老翁  poplar
策划   baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
颤抖海 Shivering Sea
百度冰与火之歌贴吧 & 百度权力的游戏贴吧
联合出品
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》
改编
原著
乔治・R・R・马丁
魁
尔
斯
Q
ar
th
权力的游戏
第二季 第五集
衣柜字幕组
第五集
“古堡幽灵”
"The Ghost of Harrenhal"
- 你发誓？ - 以圣母之名
- you swear it? - by the mother.
我儿对铁王座毫无兴趣
My son has no interest in the Iron Throne.
凯特琳・徒利
史塔克夫人
蓝礼・拜拉席恩
在高庭的王
那我们之间就没有理由敌对了
Then I see no reason for hostility between us.
您儿子可以继续自封为北境之王
Your son can go on calling himself King in the North,
卡林湾以北都将属于史塔克家族
the Starks will have dominion over all lands North of Moat Cailin,
只要他宣誓效忠于我
Provided he swears me an oath of fealty.
宣誓什么？
And the wording of this oath?
跟十八年前奈德・史塔克 对劳勃的宣誓一样
The same Ned Stark swore to Robert 18 years ago.
凯特 他们的友谊让王国归于一统
Cat, their friendship held the kingdoms together.
那么 以我儿之效忠 有何回报？
And in return for my son's loyalty?
明天早晨我将会击溃我哥哥的军队
In the morning i'll destroy my brother's army.
在那之后
When that's done,
拜拉席恩和史塔克将会并肩作战
Baratheon and Stark will fight
对付共同的敌人
Their common enemy together,
和以往的许多次一样
As they have done many times before.
我们两家素来亲近
Our two houses have always been close,
因此我恳请您重新考虑一下
Which is why I am begging you to reconsider this battle.
终止战争 与您的哥哥谈判议和吧
Negotiate a peace with your brother.
与史坦尼斯谈判议和？
Negotiate with Stannis?
您也见到他那副德行了
You heard him out there.
真不如让我去和狂风理论
I'd have better luck debating the wind.
请把我的条件带给您儿子
Please bring my terms to your son.
我相信我们生来就该是盟友
I believe we are natural allies.
我希望他也这么看
I hope he feels the same.
如若我们携手 两周之内便能结束这场战争
Together we could end this war in a fortnight.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
不！
No!
- 不！ - 跟我来！
- No. - Follow me!
- 你必须为此偿命！ - 别  等等  不是她！
- you'll die for this. - no, wait, it wasn't her!
我们得离开此地
We've got to leave.
他们会为此而绞死你的
They'll hang you for this.
- 在国王的营帐里面  快去！ - 快！
Inside the king's tent, go! - now!
我不能就这么抛下他
I won't leave him.
你若是死了 怎么替他复仇？
You can't avenge him if you're dead.
在那儿  快！
Over there, go!
别走那边
Not that way.
培提尔・贝里席
“小指头”  财政大臣
我们必须回家了
We need to go home.
- 洛拉斯 - 大人  夫人
- Loras. - My Lord, My Lady.
滚出去
Get out.
史坦尼斯一小时内就会抵达
Stannis will be here in an hour.
当他抵达时 蓝礼的封臣们会倒向他
When he arrives, Renly's bannermen will flock to him.
玛格丽・提利尔
王后 梅斯・提利尔之女
你先前的同伴们会争先恐后地
Your former companions will fight for the privilege
将你出卖给他们新的国王
Of selling you to their new king.
想必你就是来“争先”的
And you want that privilege for yourself.
你总该注意到我在向您进言
You will note that I am standing here talking to you,
- 而非史坦尼斯 - 现在不是争吵的时候
- not Stannis. - there's no time for this.
备马回高庭吧 妹妹
Ride back to Highgarden, sister.
而我绝不会躲着史坦尼斯
I'm not running from Stannis.
是塔斯的布蕾妮谋杀了蓝礼
Brienne of Tarth murdered Renly.
我不相信那个说法 你也不信
I don't believe that. you don't believe that.
谁是从吾王之死中获益最多的人？
Who gained the most from our king's death?
史坦尼斯
Stannis.
我要用剑刺穿他那张道貌岸然的脸
I will put a sword through his righteous face.
你不能留在这里
You can't stay here.
他本可以成为一个真正的国王
He would have been a true king,
一位贤明的君主
A good king.
告诉我  洛拉斯爵士
Tell me, Ser Loras,
在这世上 你最渴求什么？
What do you desire most in this world?
复仇
Revenge.
我发现复仇总是能提供最纯粹的动机
I have always found that to be the purest of motivations,
然而你不能找到刺杀史坦尼斯的机会
but you won't have a chance to put your sword through Stannis,
至少今天不能
Not today.
在他上岸之前 你早就被剁成碎片了
You'll be cut to pieces before he sets foot on solid ground.
如果你想要正义得到伸张
If it is justice that you want,
最好理智一些
Be smart about it.
躺在坟墓里可不能替他复仇
You can't avenge him from the grave.
去牵马来吧
Bring the horses.
我求你
Please.
他曾如此英俊
He was very handsome.
的确如此 陛下
He was, Your Grace.
“陛下”
"Your Grace."
自封国王是一回事 君临天下又是另一回事了
Calling yourself King doesn't make you one.
如果蓝礼不是国王 我又如何称得上王后
And if Renly wasn't a king, I wasn't a queen.
您还想当一个王后吗？
Do you want to be a queen?
不
No.
我要成为唯一的王后
I want to be the queen.
被杀了？谁干的？
Killed? by whom?
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
众说纷纭
Accounts differ.
暗指凯特琳・史塔克的好像最多
Most seem to implicate Catelyn Stark in some way.
真的？谁能这么认为？
Really? who'd have thought?
有人说是他的彩虹铁卫之一所为
Some say it was one of his own Kingsguard,
还有些人说在和谈失败之后
While still others say it was Stannis himself who did it
是史坦尼斯亲自出马杀了他
After negotiations went sour.
不管是谁干的 我都为他拍手叫好
Whomever did it, I say well done.
瓦里斯可没你叫的好听
It's not what Varys says.
他说蓝礼的军队已经转而支持史坦尼斯
He says Renly's army is flocking to support Stannis,
这使得史坦尼斯的陆军和海军数量都超过了我们
which would give Stannis superiority over us on both land and sea.
小指头说我们可以负担得起他们的三倍
Littlefinger says we can outspend him three to one.
那我只能说 父亲把你惯得太把钱当回事了
And I say father raised you to have too much respect for money.
史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩即将向我们进军
Stannis Baratheon is coming for us,
想必会很快
Sooner rather than later.
你是不是该做点别的？
Aren't there other things you should be doing,
比如把我女儿关进板条箱里以便装船送走？
like sealing my daughter in a crate so you can ship her away?
她在多恩会很安全
She'll be safer in Dorne.
当然 我知道你有多关心她的安危
Yes, I know how concerned you are for her safety.
很凑巧被你说中了
It so happens that I am.
弥赛是个甜美纯真的小姑娘
Myrcella is a sweet, innocent girl
我不会因为你而去为难她
And I don't blame her at all for you.
真是聪明
So clever.
你不觉得自己在阴谋诡计方面
Aren't you always so clever
有点太过聪明了吗？
With your schemes and your plots?
阴谋和诡计不是一回事么
Schemes and plots are the same thing.
他们就要来攻打我们了
They are going to attack us.
我们必须做好准备
We need to be ready.
你无需为此操心
No need to concern yourself over it.
国王已经亲自参与守城部署
The King is taking personal charge of siege preparations.
我能否直截了当地问一句 国王在想些什么？
May I ask specifically what the King has in mind?
管你是直截了当 还是拐弯抹角
You may specifically or you may ask vaguely.
反正答案都一样
The answer will be the same.
我们在讨论的事可不是儿戏
It's important that we talk about this.
对御前会议成员封锁敏感信息
It's the king's royal prerogative
也是国王的王室特权之一
To withhold sensitive information from his councilors.
是野火
It's wildfire.
野火？
Wildfire?
你可没对我撒过谎 对吧 堂弟？
You wouldn't lie to me, would you, cousin?
- 当然没有 - 可这明摆着是句谎话
- no. - that's a lie right there.
我没撒谎 我为什么要撒谎？
It is not a lie. why would I lie?
说说看
Tell me,
如果那些关于我哥哥和我姐姐
If the vile allegations
的恶毒诽谤不小心成真了
Against my brother and sister are true,
你觉得如果我告诉詹姆
Do you think it will make Jaime more likely
你上过她的话
To kill you or less likely?
他宰了你的可能性会有多大 嗯？
When I tell him you're fucking her, I mean.
我对您说的都是实话
I'm telling you the truth.
我看你的小命多半会变成一点抚恤金
The smart money would be on more likely.
她正在制造野火
She's making wildfire.
但他应该也会为一时冲动宰了你而后悔吧
But then perhaps his own unnatural urges will give him sympathy for yours.
炼金术士公会已经受到委任
The alchemists' guild is being commissioned.
我觉得只有一个办法可以确认此事
I suppose there's only one way to find out.
他们的地窖中贮藏了上千罐
They have thousands of pots already stored in their vaults.
他们计划将野火从城墙上投射出去
They are planning to launch them from the city walls
攻击史坦尼斯的舰队和军队
Into Stannis's ships and armies.
求您
Please.
她何时告诉你这些的？
When did she tell you this?
我偷听到她和火术士们的谈话
I heard her talking with the Pyromancer.
另一天晚上 在我离开她之后
And the other night after I left her,
她又去见了那个人
She went to meet him.
- 我发誓 - 如何发誓？
- I swear to you. - swear to me on what?
- 以我的性命起誓 - 我又不在乎你的命
- on my life. - but I don't care about your life.
以七神之荣光
In the light of the seven,
以所有的神圣公义之名
By all that is holy and right,
我 蓝赛尔・兰尼斯特 庄严起誓
I, Lancel Lannister, do solemnly vow--
好的 好的 这就够了
All right, all right. enough.
拷问你也真够无聊的
Even torturing you is boring.
出去吧
Just get out.
哦 蓝赛尔 请告知我的朋友波隆
Oh, Lancel, tell my friend Bronn
“如果在我身上发生了什么不幸 就请他宰了你”
To please kill you if anything should happen to me.
如果在提里昂大人身上发生了什么不幸 就请你宰了我
Please kill me if anything should happen to Lord Tyrion.
乐意之至
It will be my pleasure.
- 陛下 - 说
- Your Grace. - what is it?
陛下
Your Grace.
关于你弟弟的事我很遗憾 陛下
I'm sorry about your brother, Your Grace.
人们都在为他哀悼 我希望您能了解这些
I wanted to let you know that people grieve for him.
陛下
Your Grace.
- 愚人爱傻瓜 - 陛下
- fools love a fool. - Your Grace.
我也为他哀悼――那个小时候的他
I grieve for him as well-- for the boy he was,
而非长大后的他
Not the man he grew to be.
我必须和您谈谈我在洞穴里看到的一幕
I need to speak to you about what I saw in that cave.
我以为我先前说的很明白了
I thought I made it clear to you there'd be no need to
我们无需再谈此事
Speak to me on this matter.
陛下 我――
Your Grace, I--
我不记得你有健忘症
I've never known you to need to hear a thing twice.
而我也不记得您会畏惧真相
And Ive never known you to hide from the truth.
你是来跟我教授真相的？
You've come to lecture me on truth?
我是来告诉您 我看到――
I've come to tell you that what I saw--
我弟弟的封臣们现在都已集至我麾下
All my brother's bannermen have come to my side.
除了像懦夫一样逃走的提利尔家
Except the tyrells, who fled like cowards.
他们现在也构不成威胁了
They won't be able to resist us now.
很快我就会坐上铁王座
Soon I shall be sitting on the Iron Throne.
付出此等代价 真的值得吗？
Nothing is worth what this will cost you,
- 即便是为了铁―― - 关于此事 我不想再听
- not even the iron-- i'll hear no more about it.
带群人去四周巡逻
Take a company of men, secure the perimeter.
我们何时起航前往君临？
When do we sail for King's Landing?
等我的军团整合完毕后
As soon as i've consolidated my troops.
我们很快就能解决兰尼斯特的舰队
We'll make short work of the Lannisters' fleet.
一旦黑水湾的敌人被肃清
Once Blackwater Bay is cleared,
我们就能将大部队运送到城下 夺取城市
We'll deliver our troops to their doorstep and take the city.
您会带梅丽珊卓夫人一同前往吗？
And will you bring Lady Melisandre with you?
这不是你该关心的事
That's not your concern.
如果您夺取君临时将她带在身边 胜利就会属于她
If you take King's Landing with her by your side, the victory will be hers.
我从没想过需要质疑你的忠诚 我搞错了么？
I never thought I'd have reason to doubt your loyalty. Was I wrong?
忠诚的侍奉也意味着进谏难言的真相
Loyal service means telling hard truths.
哦 又是真相
Oh, truth again.
好吧 何为真相？
All right, what's the truth?
难言的真相？
The hard truth?
她是个外乡之人
She's a foreigner
前来传播她的异端信仰
Preaching her foreign religion.
有人相信只要她在您耳边低语 您便会遵从她的指示
Some believe she whispers orders in your ear and you obey.
你相信吗？
What do you believe?
您从蓝礼那里赢得了这些封臣
You won those bannermen from Renly.
不要因为她的缘故失去他们
Don't lose them to her.
我们进军君临 但是不带梅丽珊卓夫人
We set out for King's Landing without Lady Melisandre.
而你负责率领舰队进攻黑水湾
And you lead the fleet into Blackwater Bay.
陛下 我很荣幸 但是我在海上时
Your Grace, I'm honored, but my time on the sea
学会的是如何回避船只 而非攻击它们
Was spent evading ships, not attacking them.
其他的大人不会满意的
The other lords won't be happy.
这些大人没有被我以叛徒之名绞死
Most of those lords should consider themselves lucky
就该暗自庆幸了
I don't hang them for treason.
难言的真相是把双刃剑 戴佛斯爵士
Hard truths cut both ways, Ser Davos.
我抓到了！我抓到了！
I've got it! i've got it!
就是顶上那个  右边
So it's that one there at the top, on the right.
买点水果吧 大人 新鲜的水果
Buy my fruit, My Lord. fresh fruit.
史坦尼斯的步兵
Stannis has more infantry,
战船和马匹都更多
More ships, more horses.
我们又有什么？
What do we have?
你整天净操心这么些东西
There's that mind of yours you keep going on about.
哼 操心这些东西也没让我能取人性命
Well, i've never actually been able to kill people with it.
波隆
都城守备队长
那感情好 否则我早就下岗了
Good thing. i'd be out of a job.
你爹最近没给你新指示？
What about your father?
好几周没见到他的渡鸦了
He hasn't sent a raven in weeks.
他忙得很
He's very busy.
被罗柏・史塔克再三羞辱这种差事可是很费时间的
Being repeatedly humiliated by Robb Stark is time-consuming.
按照乔佛里的守城计划
We won't be able to hold the city against Stannis,
我们不可能阻止史坦尼斯破城
Not the way Joffrey's planning on holding it.
没错 就是腐坏
Corruption, yes.
人们已经变得浮夸 傲慢 恶臭不堪
We are swollen, bloated, foul.
王榻之上 姐弟私通
Brother fornicates with sister in the bed of kings
众人惊诧 他们乱伦的孽种何时会腐化变质？
and we're surprised when the fruit of their incest is rotten?
没错 腐化的国王
Yes, a rotten king.
他的论断很有说服力嘛
It's hard to argue with his assessment.
看看他对你送的命名日礼物做了些什么 就不见得了
Not after what he did to your birthday present.
那小
The King is a lost cause.
我关心的是我们这些余下的家伙
It's the rest of us I'm worried about now.
乱伦的后代在王宫里
A dancing king, prancing down his bloodstained halls
随着畸形小魔猴的笛声翩翩起舞
To the tune of a twisted demon monkey.
这家伙的想像力可真够丰富的
You have to admire his imagination.
- 他在说你呢  - 啥？
- he's talking about you. - what?
小魔猴？
Demon monkey?
民众认为国王是你的傀儡
People think you're pulling the king's strings.
他们把这城市的灾难归咎于你
They blame you for the city's ills.
归咎于我？我在尽力拯救他们啊
Blame me? I'm trying to save them.
你没必要跟我说
You don't need to convince me.
小魔猴
Demon monkey.
席恩・葛雷乔伊
来啊
Yeah, come on.
你们就是海婊子号的船员？
You're the crew of the sea bitch?
我是船长 欢迎上船
I'm your commander. welcome.
停下
Stop.
都给我停下！
Stop!
船长命令你们停下
Your Captain commands you to stop.
船长 我们这是要往哪去？
Where are we heading, Captain?
去磐石海岸 劫掠村庄
The Stony Shore to raid their villages.
只要你们干得漂亮 到时自然有大把铁钱
There'll be spoils in it for you, and women,
女人当然也不缺
If you do your jobs well.
那谁来判定我们干得漂不漂亮？
And who decides if we've done our jobs well?
当然是我了
I do.
我是船长
Your Captain.
船长 巴隆还没把你射出来的时候
I have been reaving and raping
铁钱盐妾我都有大把了
Since before you left balon's balls, Captain.
别以为你能对老子指手划脚
Don't reckon I've got much use for your ideas on how to do it.
也别以为我会把船长当回事
Don't reckon i've got much use for a Captain at all.
我告诉你 船长的事我自己都能搞定
I'm thinking I can do the job of Captain real well myself.
给我条船就够了
All I need is a ship.
你是不会乐意知道我是怎么搞到
You wouldn't know where I could find myself
这条船的 你说呢？
A ship now, would you?
你大可以这么做
You could do that,
抢下船 去哪儿都可以
Take the ship, head out on your own.
只不过我会把你拿下 拖你回来 把你锁起来
And I will hunt you down, drag you back here in chains,
以叛徒罪名吊死你
And hang you for a traitor.
别说了 我们投降
stop. we yield.
第一次当船长 可喜可贺
Congratulations on your first command.
雅拉・葛雷乔伊
谢谢你来送我
Thank you. kind of you to come see me off.
噢 我不是来送你的
Oh, I'm not here for you.
我正准备动身去红港
I was just on my way to Red Harbor.
我有三十条船 这儿都没地儿摆
I've got 30 ships. there's nowhere to put them here.
- 地儿太窄了  - 你最好现在就过去
- too narrow. - you'd better get out there.
小心你的手下私自开船出海
Wouldn't want them to set sail without you.
那不可能
That would never happen.
如果我让船员在甲板上呆一年 他们都会照做不误
My crew would wait on deck for a year if I asked them to.
但这些家伙 不太好说
This lot, though...
祝你在磐石海岸玩得愉快
Enjoy the Stony Shore.
来 跟我来
Come on, i'll take you out.
你是谁？
Who are you?
“裂颚”达格摩
你的大副 达格摩
Dagmer, your first mate.
你怎么不跟其他人一起？
Why aren't you with the rest of them?
莫非他们派你来给我领航 打算半路把我扔海里？
Or did they send you to row me out and dump me halfway in the sea?
这又够他们笑一阵的了
That would be good for a laugh.
除非你证明自己 否则他们不会尊重你
They're not gonna respect you until you prove yourself.
抢个鸟不拉屎的小渔村
And how am I supposed to prove myself by pillaging
能证明什么？
Piss-poor fishing villages?
证明不了
You're not.
可这就是我父亲派给我的任务
And yet that's the task my father has given me
靠这来证明我是真正的铁种
To prove that I'm a true Iron Islander.
他们都是铁种
They're all Iron Islanders.
他们是该听命行事还是奉行己道？
Do they do as they're told or do they do as they like?
磐石海岸离托伦方城不远
The Stony Shore's not far from Torrhen's Square.
那儿是陶哈家族的领地
The seat of the House of Tallhart--
这战利品比起渔夫女儿什么的可更有说服力
A more impressive prize than a few fishermen's daughters.
怎么 认怂了？
What, you don't think we could take it?
没 怎么可能
No, we could.
问题在于我们拿下城池以后也守不了几天
We could never hold it for more than a few days.
一旦临冬城得知我们攻克了托伦方城
As soon as Winterfell got word that we'd taken Torrhen's Square,
史塔克就会派人来把城池夺回去
The Starks would send their men to take it back.
那么――
And then--
带我上船
Take me to my ship.
史塔克延长了战线
The Starks have overextended their lines.
长夏已尽 粮草很难跟上
Now that summer's over, they'll have a hard time
他们的苦日子要来了
Keeping their men and horses fed.
北方人了解冬天比我们更甚
The Starks understand winter better than we ever will.
严寒击不倒他们
The cold won't beat them.
探子报说 有些北方领主愈发不满了
Our spies report growing discontent among the Northern lords.
他们想早点回家
They want to return home
赶在庄稼烂掉之前收割了
And gather the harvest before the crops turn.
而我也确信这问题同样存在于我们自己的封臣之中
And I'm sure if those same spiessnuck into our own encampments.
我相信他们也会回报说南方领主同样愈发不满
they would report growing discontent amongst the southern lords.
战争嘛 没人会满足
This is war; no one's content.
长久以来 我们低估了史塔克小子
We've underestimated the Stark boy for too long.
他很有战争头脑 他的手下也敬仰他
He has a good mind for warfare, his men worship him.
只要他接连打胜仗
And as long as he keeps winning battles,
他们就永远相信他是北境之王
They'll keep believing he is King in the North.
你们坐等他打败仗
You've been waiting for him to fail.
我们不出手
He is not going to fail,
他怎么能吃败仗
Not without our help.
那么我们该怎么出手？
So how do we stop him?
大人 我们整夜没合眼
We've worked through the niht, My Lord.
或许睡点觉会事半功倍
Perhaps we'd profit from some sleep.
雷吉诺 我觉得也是
As I think you would, Reginald.
想到你是我族亲
And because you're my cousin,
大家睡觉的时候你也得给我醒着
I might even let you wake from that sleep.
走吧 你妻子肯定很想你
Go, I'm sure your wife must miss you.
我妻子在兰尼斯港
My wife's in Lannisport.
那么你得快马加鞭了
Well, then you'd better start riding.
趁我没改主意把你的脑袋送还她之前 赶紧走
Go before I change my mind and send her your head.
要不是你姓兰尼斯特
If your name wasn't Lannister,
厨子帐篷里那些锅就该你去擦了 滚！
You'd be scrubbing out pots in the cook's tent. go!
不要酒 倒水
Not wine, water.
我们还要在这好一会儿
We'll be here for some time.
姑娘
Girl.
你家在哪儿？
Where are you from?
回大人 女泉城
Maidenpool, My Lord.
女泉城是谁家的封地？
And who are the lords of Maidenpool?
- 帮我想想  - 回大人 是慕顿家族
- remind me. - House Mooton, My Lord.
他们的族徽是？
And what is their sigil?
红色鲑鱼
A red salmon.
女泉城的姑娘理应知道这些
I think a Maidenpool girl would remember that.
你是个北方人吧？
You're a Northerner, aren't you?
很好 再问一次 你家在哪儿？
Good. one more time, where are you from?
回大人 是荒冢屯 达斯丁家族的封地
Barrowton, My Lord. House Dustin.
黑色王冠下的交叉双斧
Two crossed longaxes beneath a black crown.
北方人怎么说罗柏・史塔克？
And what do they say of Robb Stark in the North?
他们叫他少狼主
They call him the Young Wolf.
还有呢？
And?
他们说他骑着一头巨大的冰原狼冲锋陷阵
They say he rides into battle on the back of a giant direwolf.
他们说他可以随意变成狼身
They say he can turn into a wolf himself when he wants.
他们说他是不死的
They say he can't be killed.
那么你信这些话么？
And do you believe them?
不 大人
No, My Lord.
凡人皆有一死
Anyone can be killed.
倒水来
Fetch that water.
贾昆・赫加尔
女孩不说话
A girl says nothing.
女孩嘴紧闭
A girl keeps her mouth closed.
没有人听得到
No one hears,
朋友之间说悄悄话 好不好？
And friends may talk in secret, yes?
小子变做女孩
A boy becomes a girl.
我本来就是女孩
I was always a girl.
某人早就知道
And I was always aware.
但女孩有秘密
But the girl keeps secrets.
某人不说破
It is not for a man to spoil them.
你现在跟他们一伙
You're one of them now.
早知道我就让你烧死算了
I should have let you burn.
现在你给他们取水
And you fetch water for one of them now.
你和某人 谁对谁错？
Why is this right for you and wrong for me?
我没得选择
I didn't have a choice.
你有 某人便是自己选择
You did. I did.
你和某人同在此
And here we are.
某人要还债
A man pays his debts.
某人欠三条
A man owes three.
三条？
Three what?
红神是债主 可爱的女孩
The Red God takes what is his, lovely girl.
惟有死亡方能换取生命
And only death may pay for life.
女孩救了某人和另外两人
You saved me and the two I was with.
女孩取走三条本属于红神的命
You stole three deaths from the Red God.
就得拿三条命来偿还
We have to give them back.
女孩说名字
Speak three names
某人去办事
And the man will do the rest.
你有三条命 不多也不少
Three lives I will give you--
三条之后 我们两清
No more, no less, and we're done.
我随便说个名字
I can name anyone
你都可以杀了他？
And you'll kill him?
某人如是说
A man has said.
折磨大家的那个人
The one who tortures everyone.
某人需要名字
A man needs a name.
我不知道他的名字
I don't know his name.
他们叫他“记事本”
They call him the Tickler.
足够
That is enough.
走吧 女孩 你的大人口渴了
Go now, girl. your master is thirsty.
他还没回来
He's not here yet.
他本应找见我们 吹响号角
He'd have seen us, blown the horn.
他什么时候回来？
When will he come?
断掌会掌握好时间
The Halfhand does things in his own time.
我叔叔跟我讲过他的故事
My uncle told me stories about him.
那些故事大多是真事
Most of them are true.
我听说上次冬天 断掌有一半时间都在长城之外
I heard the Halfhand spent half of last winter beyond the wall.
是整个冬天
The whole winter.
他被大雪堵在了风声峡以北
He was North of the Skirling Pass when the snows came.
只好等到冰雪消融
Had to wait for the thaw.
这么说独自一人在这里活下去也不是不可能啊
So it is possible for someone to survive out here on their own.
对于断掌来说的确有可能
Well, possible for the Halfhand.
漂亮吧？
Beautiful, isn't it?
吉莉会喜欢上这儿的
Gilly would love it here.
没什么比恋爱中的男人更恶心了
There's nothing more sickening than a man in love.
艾迪森・托勒特
忧郁的艾迪
葛兰
先民拳峰
不停做点事
About time you did something.
至少会暖和点
At least you'll keep warm.
先民拳峰
The fist of the First Men.
想想这里有多古老――
Think of how old this place is--
那时坦格利安还没征服安达尔人
Before the Targaryens defeated the Andals,
那时维斯特洛的主人还是先民 不是安达尔人
Before the Andals took Westeros from the First Men.
那时我还没死 别说了 谢谢
Before I die, please, stop talking.
几千几万年之前
Thousands and thousands of years ago,
先民们就站在我们现在所站的位置上
The First Men stood here where we're standing
度过漫漫长夜
All through the long night.
你们觉得他们长什么样？我是说先民
What do you think they were like, the First Men?
顶着木头脑壳
Stupid.
脑袋正常的人才不会跑到这个破地方来
Smart people don't find themselves in places like this.
我觉得他们满脸恐惧
I think they were afraid.
我觉得他们是来这里躲避什么东西的
I think they came here to get away from something.
我觉得他们没能躲开
And I don't think it worked.
野人袭击？
Wildlings?
一声号角 兄弟归来
One blast is for rangers returning.
两声号角才是野人来袭
Wildlings is two blasts.
所以你得一直等待着
So you got to stand there waiting,
揣测着结果
Wondering.
一声是兄弟
One blast for friends,
两声是敌人
Two for foes.
三声 是异鬼
And three for White Walkers.
但是一千年来
It's been 1,000 years,
吹三声号角的遭数只有一次
But that's the only time they blow the horn three times.
既然是一千年前的事 你怎么知道？
But if it's been 1,000 years, how do yu know?
- 那个……  - 我从书里看到的
- Well... - I read it in a book.
瞧
Look.
是断掌科林
It's Qhorin Halfhand.
没错 可以多活一天了
Aye, we'll live another day.
真是万幸
Hurrah.
大人 小心点
Take care, My Lord.
我记得一句水手们的俗语――
I remember reading an old sailor's proverb--
“撒尿浇野火 提裤做太监”
"piss on wildfire and your cock burns off."
噢 我没做过这样的实验
Oh, I have not conducted this experiment.
不过应该差不离
It could well be true.
这种物质火焰极热
The substance burns so hot,
可以烧融木头 石头 甚至钢材
It melts wood, stone, even steel,
哈林
火术士
当然 烧融血肉不在话下
And, of course, flesh.
这种物质火焰极热 血肉遇着它就跟油脂一样
The substance burns so hot, it melts flesh like tallow.
自从龙消失之后 野火就成了
After the Dragons died, wildfire was the key
坦格利安家统治的关键
To the Targaryen power.
我的伙伴有话要说
my companion takes issue.
我告诉你 推着小车到军营周围
If I could tell you how many crazy old men
把他们那些装着猪屎的罐子吹得神乎其神
I've seen pushing carts around army camps
这样的疯老头子我见得多了……
Making grand claims about jars full of pig shit...
- 无意冒犯  - 我们不是卖猪屎的
- no offense meant. - our order does not deal in pig shit.
这种物质看起来像火
The substance is fire given form.
在梅葛王的时代我们完善了配方
And we have been perfecting it since the days of Maegor.
用来干嘛？
To do what?
把罐子架在投石机上 往敌军阵营里投
The jars are put in catapults and flung at the enemy.
你手头有多少存货？
How much do you have?
就算你能找到训练有素的士兵来操作投石机
If you could get real soldiers to man the catapults,
也不见得能十次打中一次
Then maybe you'd hit your target one time in 10,
况且训练有素的士兵全被你父亲带到河间地去了
but all the real soldiers are in the Riverlands with your father.
大人 这个人在侮辱我
My Lord, this man is insulting.
我不知道你见没见过打仗 老头
I don't know if you've ever seen a battle, old man,
但是现在情况有点麻烦
But things can get a bit messy.
因为当我们把这玩意丢向史坦尼斯的时候
'cause when we're flinging things at Stannis,
他也会把它们丢回来
He's flinging them right back at us.
我们的人会死 会吓得尿裤子 最后逃跑
Men die, men shit themselves, men run,
这意味着两败俱伤
Which means pots falling,
意味着城内也要遭受焚烧
Which means fire inside the walls,
意味着这本意拿来守卫城市的昏招
Which means the poor cunts trying to defend the city
最后反而把城市烧没了
End up burning it down.
我的朋友还是持怀疑态度
My friend remains unconvinced.
要是伊里斯・坦格利安在世的时候
He would not dare insult my order
他可不敢对我的建议如此无礼
Whilst aerys Targaryen lived.
但是他早就死了
Well, he's not living anymore.
而且这么多野火罐子也没帮上他什么忙 不是么？
And all his pots of wildfire didn't help him, did they?
打胜仗靠的是人 可不是什么魔术戏法
Men win wars, not magic tricks.
自从您姐姐太后陛下下令以来
We have been working tirelessly day and night
我们不知疲倦 日夜劳作
Ever since your royal sister commanded us to do so.
目前我们已经拥有
Our present count stands
7811罐
At 7,811,
足够将史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩的舰队和军队
Enough to burn Stannis Baratheon's fleet
全部烧光
And armies both.
狗屁主意
This is a shit idea.
恐怕我得赞同我的顾问 哈林智者
I'm afraid I have to concur with my advisor, wisdom Hallyne.
这房间里的东西会把整个君临都毁掉
Te contents of this room could lay King's Landing low.
你不必再为我姐姐制作野火了
You won't be making wildfire for my sister any longer.
来为我做
You'll be making it for me.
龙焰
Dracarys.
多莉亚
龙焰
Dracarys.
今后他就可以养活自己了
He'll be able to feed himself from now on.
让他睡一会 多莉亚
Let him sleep, Doreah.
遵命 卡丽熙
Yes, Khaleesi.
他喜欢你
He loves you.
伊丽
我把顶部的这一部分去掉
然后把鞋跟固定在这里
谢谢你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
看到札罗为你订做的衣服了吗？
Did you see the dress Xaro had made for you?
他们说他是魁尔斯最富有的人
They say he's the wealthiest man in Qarth.
大家都知道
It is known.
而且如果魁尔斯是厄索斯大陆最富有的城市――
And if Qarth is the wealthiest city in Essos--
上次有个富人送我衣服
The last time a rich man gave me a dress,
是为了把我卖给卓戈卡奥
He was selling me to Khal Drogo.
愿他永在夜间国度骑着骏马
札罗对我们款待有加 但我们对他一无所知
Xaro is our host, but we know nothing about him.
当人们心情愉悦的时候
Men like to talk about other men
就喜欢谈论其他人
When they're happy.
在札罗的宴会上 您看起来会像一位真正的公主――
You would look like a real princess in Xaro's--
她不是什么公主 是我们的卡丽熙
She's not a princess. she's a Khaleesi.
他们邀请您为上宾
You should wear it, Khaleesi.
出于礼貌
You are their guest.
您该更衣了 卡丽熙
It would be rude not to.
你一定要去逛逛夜市
And you must visit the night market.
魁尔斯的夜市绝对是你前所未见
The Qartheen night market is like no night market you've ever seen.
听起来棒极了
it sounds wonderful.
弥林人觉得他们有个夜市
The Meereens think they have a night market.
我会亲自带您去看看
I will take you there myself.
抱歉我要失陪一会
Please excuse me for a moment.
他们在做什么
What are they doing?
马拉科说这雕像太重了没法带
Malakko says the statue is too heavy to carry.
卡瓦罗说马拉科是个白痴
Kovarro says that Malakko is an idiot.
他们可以把宝石挖出来 剩下的部分是纯金
They can pry out the gems, the rest is pure gold.
非常柔软 他可以砍下能搬走的部分
Very soft. he can chop off as much as we can carry.
或者融掉它 非常简单
我们是来做客的！
你们不许挖掉宝石或是砍掉 融掉金子
当然不是现在 卡丽熙！
我们会等到离开的时候
离开的时候也不行！
为什么不行？
这里的主人把我们从红色荒原中挽救出来
你却想偷走他的东西作为回报？
我可不要再听见这样的话
我哥哥说过 多斯拉克人唯一懂得的事
My brother used to say the only thing the Dothraki knew how to do
就是把上等人建好的东西偷过来
Was steal things better men have built.
那可不是他们唯一会的
It's not the only thing.
他们杀起上等人来更在行
They're quite good at killing the better men.
我可不会变成那样的女王
That's not the kind of queen I'm going to be.
龙之母
Mother of Dragons.
俳雅・菩厉
男巫
我代表魁尔斯的巫师
On behalf of the warlocks of Qarth,
欢迎您的到来
I welcome you.
为了证明诚意
A demonstration?
请收下这块宝石 看看它
Take this gem. look at it.
多么深邃
Into its depths.
有这么多面
So many facets.
靠近一点你就能从里面看到自己的身影
Look closely enough and you can see yourself in them.
往往不只一个
often more than once.
您对札罗的便宜货和小玩意厌倦了吗
Should you grow tired of Xaro's baubles and trinkets,
如果您能光临不朽之殿 我将感到无比荣幸
it would be an honor to host you at the House of the Undying.
我们永远期待您的到来
You're always welcome,
龙之母
Mother of Dragons.
非常抱歉
My apologies.
俳雅・菩厉是十三巨子之一
Pyat Pree is one of the Thirteen.
我只是出于惯例邀请他出席
It was customary for me to extend him an invitation.
在魁尔斯大家总是遵从惯例
Customs die slow deaths in Qarth.
什么是不朽之殿
What is the House of the Undying?
是巫师们翻看积灰的书籍
It is where the warlocks go to squint at dusty books
饮下夜影之水的地方
And drink shade of the evening.
那会让他们的嘴唇变蓝 把他们的脑筋变得迷糊
It turns their lips blue and their minds soft--
迷糊到 他们会把
So soft, they actually believe
自己那些小把戏当成魔法
Their parlor tricks are magic.
你要盯紧她
You watch over her.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
我认识你
I know you.
魁蜥
亚夏的缚影士
熊岛的乔拉・莫尔蒙
Jorah Mormont of Bear Island.
你是谁
Who are you?
我只是个无名小卒
I'm no one.
但她是龙之母
But she is the Mother of Dragons.
她比任何时候都需要真正的护卫
She needs true protectors now more than ever.
他们会不分日夜来访
They shall come day and night
来观赏这重临人间的奇迹
To see the wonder born into the world again.
一旦他们看见
And when they see, they shall lust,
就会对这能焚毁一切的龙焰起贪念
For Dragons are fire made flesh.
龙焰就是力量
And fire is power.
那影子看起来像是史坦尼斯
It looked like Stannis.
对我来说它只是
To me it just looked like...
一个人形影子
A shadow in the shape of a man.
是史坦尼斯形状
In the shape of Stannis.
明天我们就能到达我儿子的营帐
We should reach my son's camp tomorrow.
您会在那里常驻吗 夫人
Will you stay there long, My Lady?
我只打算把所见所闻告诉罗柏
Only long enough to tell Robb what I have seen.
然后就启程回临冬城
After that, I will leave for Winterfell.
两个小儿子需要我
My two youngest need me.
我离开他们太久了
I've been away from them for far too long.
我从没见过我的母亲
I never knew my mother.
非常遗憾
I'm sorry.
我的母亲因为难产而去世的时候
My own mother died on the birthing bed
我还很小
When I was very young.
太残酷了
It's a bloody business.
后来发生的一切更加艰难
What comes after is even harder.
一旦您安全回到自己的人民当中
Once you're safely back amongst your own people,
就准许我离开吗 夫人
Will you give me leave to go, My Lady?
你想杀史坦尼斯
You mean to kill Stannis.
我发过誓
I swore a vow.
但是史坦尼斯军容强盛
But Stannis has a great army around him.
他身边也有许多发誓守护他的侍卫
His own guards are sworn to keep him safe.
我绝不比他们任何一个差
I'm as good as any of them.
我当初就不该退缩
I should never have fled.
蓝礼的死不是你的错
Renly's death was no fault of yours.
你曾忠勇地为他效命
You served him bravely.
我只在他临死的时候
I only held him that once
才抱过他一次
As he was dying.
他已经不在了 布蕾妮
He's gone, Brienne.
要是你追随他一同赴死 你的侍奉就没有任何意义
You serve nothing and no one by following him into the earth.
蓝礼的敌人也是罗柏的敌人
Renly's enemies are Robb's enemies as well.
我不认识您的儿子 夫人
I do not know your son, My Lady...
但我愿意为您效劳 如果您接受的话
But I could serve you if you would have me.
你很勇敢
You have courage.
也许 那不是浴血沙场的勇气
Not battle courage, perhaps,
但 我不知道
But, I don't know,
那是女人特有的勇气
A woman's kind of courage.
而且我相信一旦时机来临
And I think that when the time comes,
您一定不会强留我
You will not hold me back.
请答应我不会强行阻止我
Promise me that you will not hold me back
去找史坦尼斯报仇
From Stannis.
一旦时机来临 我绝不会强留你
When the time comes, I will not hold you back.
我是您的人了 夫人
Then I am yours, My Lady.
我会保护您的安全
I will shield your back
危难之际我愿奉献我的生命
And give my life for yours if it comes to that.
以新旧诸神之名 我郑重起誓
I swear it by the Old Gods and the new.
我起誓 你将永远在我家中拥有一席之地
I vow that you shall always have a place in my home
和我同桌而食
And at my table
我誓言永不让你的服务
And that I shall ask no service of you
蒙上不誉的污名
That might bring you dishonor.
以新旧诸神之名 我郑重起誓
I swear it by the Old Gods and the new.
那可不光是小偷 大人
And it's not just thieves, My Lord.
他们的山上现在都是狼
There's wolves in them hills now,
我从没见过这么多
More than i've ever seen.
他们在晚上闯入然后杀死我的羊
They come down in the night and they kill my sheep.
我的三个儿子一直为你的哥哥作战 大人
My three sons is away fighting for your brother, My Lord.
他们会一直战斗下去
They'll fight, keep fighting
直到允许回家
Till they're told to go home.
我身边现在没人能保护我的羊群了 只有我自己
I have no one to man my flock now. only me.
我可不能整日整夜地守着
I can't keep watch all day and all night.
我们可以派两个避冬市镇的孤儿跟你回去
We can send two orphan boys from Winterstown home with you
帮你照看羊群
To help watch over your flock
如果你愿意为他们提供房间和面包
If you can give them room and board.
我老婆一直祈祷多生几个孩子
My wife always prayed for more children.
我们会好好照看他们的 非常感谢 大人
We'll look after them. thank you, My Lord.
诸神保佑您和您的家人
And may the Gods bless you and yours.
别砸了
stop it.
如果后面没人了 我想趁天黑前出去骑一会马
If that's everyone, I'm going to go for a ride before dark.
- 好的  - 阿多
- good. - Hodor.
- 阿多  - 布兰  史塔克大人
- Hodor - Bran--Lord Stark.
托伦方城被包围了
Torrhen's Square is under siege.
托伦方城离这儿只有40里格远
Torrhen's Square is barely 40 leagues from here.
兰尼斯特怎么能那么快打到北方来
How can the Lannisters strike so far North?
可能是魔山带领的一队骑兵
Might be a raiding party led by the Mountain.
也可能是泰温・兰尼斯特雇来的佣兵团
Might be sellswords paid by Tywin Lannister.
我们必须解救他们
We have to help them.
大部分能上战场的都跟着罗柏走了
Most of the fighting men are away with Robb,
但我可以勉强凑上200个人
But I can gather 200 decent men.
需要这么多吗
Do you need so many?
如果不能保护我们的封臣
If we can't protect our own bannermen,
他们又何必保护我们
Why should they protect us?
去吧 罗德利克爵士 带上你需要的人
Go, Ser Rodrik. take the men you need.
我不会去太久的 大人
Won't take long, My Lord.
南方人在这坚持不了多久
Southerners don't do well up here.
那么 这预示了什么
So, what does it mean?
问你的鲁温师傅
Ask your Maester Luwin.
他不是一直在读书么
He's the one studying books all the time.
我问过他 可他从没听过三眼乌鸦
I did ask him. he'd never heard of a three-eyed raven.
- 那就什么也说明不了  - 你骗人
- must not mean anything, then. - you're lying.
您可能会是我的小主人 但别说我骗人
You might be a little lord, but don't you call me a liar.
-你明明知道  - 我可从来没这么说过
- you know what it means. - I never said I didn't.
你没有如实回答我
You didn't give me an honest answer.
那和骗子可不一样
That's not the same as being a liar.
是吗 我看差不多
Well, it's not far off.
所以你再也没梦见过三眼乌鸦吗
So, you've been dreaming of a three-eyed raven again?
在神木林 你说你没有做梦
In the Godswood, you told me you didn't dream.
现在谁是骗子
Now who's a liar?
你在梦里看见了什么？
What did you see in your dream?
不好的事？
Something bad?
告诉我 孩子
Tell me, boy.
我梦见海水涌向临冬城
I dreamt that the sea came to Winterfell.
我看见海浪冲向大门
I saw waves crashing against the gates
然后海水淹没了城墙……
And the water came flowing over the walls...
淹没了城堡
Flooded the castle.
淹死的人们漂浮在水面上
Drowned men were floating here
就在院子里
In the yard.
罗德利克爵士也在其中
Ser Rodrik was one of them.
大海离这有好几百里呢
The sea is hundreds of miles away.
我知道
I know.
不过是个愚蠢的梦
It's just a stupid dream.
我得把这些土豆拿去厨房
I've got to get these potatoes to the kitchen.
不然他们又要把我锁起来了
Otherwise they'll put me in chains again.
欧莎
Osha.
三眼乌鸦
The three-eyed raven,
长城以北的人
What do they say about it
怎么说它？
North of the wall?
在长城以北 他们会说出各种各样的疯话
They say all sorts of crazy things North of the wall.
- 在那  - 哪？
- There.  - Where?
山上
On that Mountain.
我看不大清楚
I don't see very well.
有火
A fire.
“断掌”科林
守夜人
那里有火光
There's a fire.
围绕火堆坐着的那些人可比咱们看得清楚多了
The people sitting around it have better eyes than yours or mine.
既然他们看见我们来了  火光就是个信号
When they see us coming, that fire becomes a signal.
给曼斯充足的时间来和我们作战
Gives Mance Rayder plenty of time to throw a party in our honor.
他手下有多少野人？
How many wildlings have joined him?
据我们所知 全部的
From what we can tell, all of them.
就像鹿群对抗狼群一样 曼斯把他们集合在一起
Mance has gathered them all like deer against the wolves.
他们几乎已经准备好采取行动了
They're almost ready to make their move.
在哪？
Where?
安全的某处
Somewhere safe.
南方某处
Somewhere south.
我们既不能盲目冲他们的包围圈
Can't just march into their midst.
也不能躲在一堆石头后面
And we can't wait for them here with nothing but a pile
坐以待毙
Of stones to protect us.
你是说我们应该返回长城？
You saying we should fall back to the wall?
曼斯曾是我们的一员
Mance was one of us once.
现在是他们的人
Now he's one of them.
他会向他们传授我们的行事之道
He's gonna teach them our way of doing things.
他们会以武力发起强攻
They'll hit us in force.
即便我们狠狠回击 他们没那么容易善罢甘休
And they won't run away when we hit back.
他们会比从前更组织有序
They're gonna be more organized than before,
更训练有素
More disciplined
更像我们
More like us.
所以我们要伪装成他们
So we need to be more like them,
要照他们的方式行事
Do things their way.
潜入内部  杀了曼斯
Sneak in, kill mance,
在他们能进攻长城之前
And scatter them to the winds
就让他们土崩瓦解
Before they can march on the wall.
而要这么做...
And to do that...
我们就得脱下这身行头
We need to get rid of those lookouts.
这任务不需要四百多号人
It's not a job for 400 men.
要干得迅速和悄无声息
I need to move fast and silent.
哈克 石蛇 博尔巴
Harker, Stonesnake, Borba.
总司令大人  我请求加入科林大人的队伍
Lord Commander, i'd like to join Lord Qhorin.
我有过各种各样的诨名
I've been called lots of things,
但还是头回听人叫我科林大人
But that might be my first Lord Qhorin.
你是个事务官 雪诺 不是游骑兵
You're a steward, snow, not a ranger.
我和尸鬼交过手 还杀了一个
I've fought and killed a Wight.
有几个游骑兵有资格这么说？
How many rangers can say that?
就是他？
He's the one?
你是杀过个尸鬼
Aye. you killed a Wight.
但也被一个老头揍了个半死
You also let an old man
还被抢走了剑
Beat you bloody and take your sword.
卡斯特？
Craster?
为这孩子说句公道话 那家伙可是只难缠的老山羊
In the boy's defense, that's a tough old goat.
我能在琼恩离开后接替事务官的职务 司令官大人
I could take up jon's duties while he's gone, My Lord.
不会有问题的
It would be no trouble.
那好吧 我希望你做个游骑兵
Well, I hope you make a better ranger
比你做事务官要出色
Than you do a steward.
去吧
Go on.
那 告诉我
So, tell me,
你的男仆恋上你多久了？
How long has your manservant been in love with you?
他不是我的男仆  而且他也没爱上我
He's not my manservant and he's not in love with me.
他是我的顾问
He's my advisor,
和挚友
My friend.
不一定噢
Unlikely.
我总能看穿一个男人的欲望
I can almost always tell what a man wants.
那女人的欲望呢？
And what about what a woman wants?
复杂多了
Much more complicated.
比方说 你
You, for example,
你想要什么？
What do you want?
越过狭海  夺回铁王座
To cross the Narrow Sea and take back the Iron Throne.
为什么呢？
Why?
因为我向我的卡拉萨许诺会保护他们
Because I promised my Khalasar i'd protect them
并给他们找个家园
and find them a safe home.
你为了多斯拉克人征服七国？
You want to conquer the Seven Kingdoms for the Dothraki?
我想要七国 因为它们本就依法属于我
I want them because they're mine by right.
铁王座是我的 我会夺回它
The Iron Throne is mine and I will take it.
啊 一位征服者
Ah, a conqueror.
那你又是如何得到这一切的？
And how did you get all of this?
-谁给你的？  -不
- did someone give it to you? - no.
我一无所有
I come from nothing.
像个货物一样压在舱底运来这里
I hit the docks like a piece of cargo,
只不过  假如真是货物 还会有人关心
Except someone normally cares what happens to cargo.
所以你获得了你欲求不满的一切
So you wanted more than you had and you took it.
你也算是个征服者 只是野心不够
You're a conqueror, too. you're just less ambitious.
嗯
Mmm.
你的野心何在  札罗・赞旺・达梭斯？
What do you want, Xaro Zhoan Daxos?
在城门口  你为我歃血担保
At the gates of the city, you bled for me.
为了什么？
Why?
我会告诉你为何
I will show you why.
这门与拱顶是由瓦雷利亚石打造
The door and the vault is made of Valyrian stone.
再强的金属也留不下个印
The hardest steel does not make a mark.
我曾向魁尔斯最杰出的锁匠们提出悬赏
I offered the greatest locksmiths in Qarth
如果他们闯入就赐给他们同体重的黄金
Their weight in gold if they could break into it.
我还将同样的赏赐许诺给最伟大的窃贼们
I made the same offer to the greatest thieves.
但他们统统铩羽而归
They all went home empty-handed.
能开启此门的
The only thing that can open this door
唯有这钥匙
Is this key.
而门后的财宝？
And behind the door?
都可以归属于我？
And it can all be mine?
全部？
All?
要我说 一半归你
Let us say half.
那也将远超购买马匹 舰只 军队的开销
More than enough to buy horses, ships, armies--
足够送你回家
Enough to go home.
而我要做的呢？
All I have to do?
嫁给我吧
Is marry me.
这真是个浪漫的求婚
That was a romantic proposal.
我已结过一次婚
I've already married once for love,
但诸神将她从我身边夺去
But the Gods stole her from me.
我曾家徒四壁
I come from nothing.
双亲穷得连鞋都买不起
My mother and father never owned a pair of shoes.
但你若答应嫁给我 我会将七国拱手奉上
But marry me and I will give you the seven kingdoms
而我们的后代将成为王子与公主
And our children will be princes and princesses.
看见了吧
See?
我的雄心远超过你的想像
I have more ambition than you thought.
事不宜迟 丹妮莉丝・坦格利安
The time is right, Daenerys Targaryen,
女王一世
First of your name.
劳勃・拜拉席恩已死
Robert Baratheon is dead.
如果你带着雇佣军跨过狭海--
If you cross the sea with an army you bought--
七国上下早已战乱四起
The Seven Kingdoms are at war with one another.
四位伪王在毁灭国家
Four false kings destroying the country.
要想赢回维斯特洛 你需要来自维斯特洛的支持
To win Westeros, you need support from Westeros.
篡夺者已死
The usurper is dead.
狼与狮子又争斗不堪
The Starks fight the Lannisters,
而拜拉席恩则兄弟相残
And Baratheons fight each other.
就凭你那位割手为盟的新朋友
According to your new friend
信口开河的这么说？
Who earned your trust by cutting his hand?
时不我待了 我们急需舰队与军队
The time to strike is now. we need to find ships and an army
否则我们这辈子就只能困在世界的角落
Or we'll spend the rest of our lives rotting away
慢慢腐烂了
At the edge of the world.
富翁之所以富有 可不是因为他们做赔钱买卖
Rich men do not become rich by giving more than they get.
他们给了你船与士兵就从此掌控了你
They'll give you ships and soldiers and they'll own you forever.
谨慎而行虽然艰辛但绝无差错
Moving carefully is the hard way, but it's the right way.
但我要在魁尔斯的门外
And if i'd listened to that advice
听从了这番建议 我们早就葬身荒野
Outside the gates of Qarth, we'd all be dead by now.
我知道你把眼下这机遇看做最后希望
I know the opportunity before you seems like the last you'll ever have,
但你要--
But you must--
别把我当小孩教训
Do not speak to me like I'm a child.
-我只想   -你只想什么？
- I only want - what do you want?
告诉我
Tell me.
把你送上铁王座
To see you on the Iron Throne.
-为了什么？  -你的权力
- why? - you have a good claim.
头衔  与生俱来的权利
A title. a birthright.
但你还拥有更高尚的东西
But you have something more than that.
即便你掩饰或是否认也好 但你的确拥有一颗仁慈之心
You may cover it up and deny it,but you have a gentle heart.
你将不仅仅会被尊重和敬畏
You would not only be respected and feared,
你也将获得爱戴
You would be loved.
你就是那个命中注定而且能力卓著的王者
Someone who can rule and should rule.
前无古人后无来者地
Centuries come and go without a person like that
出现在这个世上
Coming into the world.
有时候我忍不住看向你时
There are times when I look at you
仍不敢相信你是真的
And still can't believe you're real.
那么作为我的顾问  你又有何良策？
So what would you have me do as my advisor?
自力更生
Make your own way.
找到属于你自己的船只 只需要一艘就足够
Find your own ship. you only need one.
我们的盟友在维斯特洛  而非魁尔斯
The allies we need are in Westeros, not Qarth.
那我又如何找到那艘船？
And how do I get the ship?
我来替你找
I'll find it for you.
可靠的船与船长
A sound ship with a good Captain.
我期待见到他
I look forward to meeting him.
卡丽熙
Khaleesi.
你应该侧身站
You should stand sideface.
侧身？
Sideface?
侧面向敌
Sideways.
-为什么？  -更难被命中
- why? - smaller target.
我有说要跟别人打架么？
Am I fighting someone?
你为战斗而练习
You're practicing for a fight.
那就该用正确的方式
You should practice right.
守卫！
Guards!
-来帮忙  -你看见了什么？
- help. - did you see anything?
上到那里去 去看看他从哪跌下来的
Go up there. go and see where he fell from.
去那后面
Go up the back.
这真蹊跷
That is strange.
走开
Move away.
都退后  他挂了
Stand back. He's dead.
衣柜字幕组出品